[
  {
    "question": "Information Technology Act, 2000 (India) comes into existence in INDIA on",
    "options": { "A": "17th October 2000", "B": "27th November 2003", "C": "1st January 2006", "D": "17th October 2009" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "How E-waste results in data theft?",
    "options": { "A": "By Email Forwarding", "B": "By Replacing Old Electronic Device in Exchange without clearing data", "C": "By Sharing Data", "D": "By Using Wi-Fi Network" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "Plagiarism means",
    "options": { "A": "An Act of presenting another personâ€™s work or idea as your own", "B": "A disease that affects humans and other mammals", "C": "A contagious bacterial disease characterized by fever", "D": "None of Above" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a part of CIA Triad?",
    "options": { "A": "Confidentiality", "B": "Integrity", "C": "Availability", "D": "Phishing" },
    "correct": "D"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which toll free number a complaint can be registered with Punjab Police Cyber Crime Division in case of any online fraud?",
    "options": { "A": "1911", "B": "1930", "C": "1947", "D": "1912" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Act in India focuses on Cyber Crime?",
    "options": { "A": "Banking Regulation Act 1949", "B": "IT Act 2000", "C": "Indian Penal Code 1860", "D": "CrPC 1973" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "Any offense committed against a person or groups of people using digital gadget is known as __________.",
    "options": { "A": "Cyber Crime", "B": "Cyber Ethics", "C": "Cyber Law", "D": "Hacking" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ refers to the code of responsible behavior on the internet.",
    "options": { "A": "Cyber Crime", "B": "Cyber Ethics", "C": "Cyber Law", "D": "Cyber Security" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "E-waste management using landfills pollute __________.",
    "options": { "A": "Underground water and soil", "B": "Air", "C": "Mountains", "D": "Forests" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "__________ is an act of secretly or stealthily listening to the private conversation or communications of others without their consent.",
    "options": { "A": "Eavesdropping", "B": "Confidentiality", "C": "Encryption", "D": "Cyber Stalking" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "CIA triad stands for __________, Integrity, and Availability.",
    "options": { "A": "Cyber Ethics", "B": "Eavesdropping", "C": "Confidentiality", "D": "Cyber Security" },
    "correct": "C"
  },
  {
    "question": "CIA triad stands for Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability.",
    "options": { "A": "True", "B": "False", "C": "Both", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "IT Act in India came into force in the year 1995.",
    "options": { "A": "True", "B": "False", "C": "Both", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "E-waste is good for human health.",
    "options": { "A": "True", "B": "False", "C": "Both", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "Cyber Ethics ensure that users understand their responsibilities for conducting themselves online.",
    "options": { "A": "True", "B": "False", "C": "Both", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hacking is used to expose vulnerabilities in systems too.",
    "options": { "A": "True", "B": "False", "C": "Both", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "A"
  },
  {
    "question": "Spying is an act of keeping a secret watch on various activities of opponents for intelligence purposes.",
    "options": { "A": "True", "B": "False", "C": "Both", "D": "None" },
    "correct": "A"
  }
]
